[
    {
      "question": "Q1. What is React primarily used for?",
      "options": ["Building databases", "Styling web pages", "Building user interfaces", "Server-side scripting"],
      "answer": "Building user interfaces"
    },
    {
      "question": "Q2. What is a component in React?",
      "options": ["database table", "A function or class that returns JSX", "A stylesheet file", "A server-side script"],
      "answer": "A function or class that returns JSX"
    },
    {
      "question": "Q3. What is JSX?",
      "options": ["A JavaScript extension that allows HTML in JS", "A CSS framework", "A type of API", "A server configuration file"],
      "answer": "A JavaScript extension that allows HTML in JS"
    },
    {
      "question": "Q4. Which hook is used to handle state in functional components?",
      "options": ["useFetch", "useData", "useState", "useRender"],
      "answer": "useState"
    },
    {
      "question": "Q5. Which method is used to pass data from parent to child component?",
      "options": ["Redux", "Props", "State", "Context"],
      "answer": "Props"
    },
    {
      "question": "Q6. Which hook is used for side effects in React?",
      "options": ["useEffect", "useSideEffect", "useState", "useReducer"],
      "answer": "useEffect"
    },
    {
      "question": "Q7. What does useEffect(() => {}, []) mean?",
      "options": ["Runs after every render", "Runs once when component mounts", "ReRuns before renderd", "Never runs"],
      "answer": "Runs once when component mounts"
    },
    {
      "question": "Q8. What is the virtual DOM?",
      "options": ["The browser DOM", "A copy of the real DOM for faster updates", "A server file system", "A database"],
      "answer": "A copy of the real DOM for faster updates"
    },
    {
      "question": "Q9. How do you create a React app easily?",
      "options": ["create-app-react", "npm init react", "create-react-app", "react-init"],
      "answer": "create-react-app"
    },
    {
      "question": "Q10. How can you handle multiple state values in one object?",
      "options": ["useEffect", "useRef", "useState with an object", "useState with array"],
      "answer": "useState with an object"
    }
  ]
  